<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Proposal for Commons/Net</title>
    <author email="brekke@apache.org">Jeffrey D. Brekke</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    
<section name="(0) Rationale">

<p>
Java doesn't provide an api for common internet protocols.  Many
applications need to communicate via well known internet protocols such as
ftp, smtp, and telnet.
</p>

</section>

<section name="(1) Scope of the Package">

<p>
The purpose of the library is to provide fundamental protocol access, 
not higher-level abstractions. Therefore, some of the design violates 
object-oriented design principles. Our philosophy is to make the global 
functionality of a protocal accesible (e.g., TFTP send file and receive 
file) when possible, but also provide access to the fundamental protocols 
where applicable so that the programmer may construct his own custom 
implementations (e.g, the TFTP packet classes and the TFTP packet send 
and receive methods are exposed).
</p>

</section>

<section name="(2) Initial Source of the Package">

<p>The initial classes came from the NetComponents project donated by Daniel Savarese of Oro Inc.</p>

<p>The proposed package name for the new component is org.apache.commons.net</p>

</section>

<section name="(3)  Required Jakarta-Commons Resources">

<ul>
<li>CVS Repository - New directory <code>net</code> in the
    <code>jakarta-commons</code> CVS repository.</li>
<li>Mailing List - Discussions will take place on the general
    <em>commons-dev@jakarta.apache.org</em> mailing list.  To help
    list subscribers identify messages of interest, it is suggested that
    the message subject of messages about this component be prefixed with
    [net].</li>
<li>Bugzilla - New component "net" under the "Commons" product
    category, with appropriate version identifiers as needed.</li>
<li>Jyve FAQ - New category "commons-net" (when available).</li>
</ul>

</section>

<section name="(4) Initial Committers">

<p>The initial committers on Commons/Net may be found  shall be as follows:
<ul>
<li>Jeffrey D. Brekke (brekke)</li>
<li>Daniel Savarese (savarese)</li>
</ul>
</p>

</section>
</body>
</document>
